[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
Before we get to gradient descent though,
قبل أن نتابع إلى الهبوط التدريجي
we need to figure out what the quality metric we're trying to optimize is.
نحن بحاجة إلى معرفة مقياس الجودة الذي نحاول تحسينه .
That quality metric is going to call the data likelihood.
حيث إن مقياس الجودة هو الذي سيستدعي احتمال البيانات.
So let's dive in and explore exactly that concept.
لذلك دعونا نبدأ ونستكشف هذا المفهوم بالضبط.
To better understand the data likelihood,
لنحصل على فهم أفضل لاحتمال البيانات،
let's start from some simple examples and try to understand what w is trying to do,
دعونا نبدأ من بعض الأمثلة البسيطة ونحاول أن نفهم ما تحاول w القيام به،
what we're trying to do here in the learning problem.
ما الذي نحاول القيام به هنا في مسألة التعلم.
So let's say that we have this data point that has two awesomes and one awful, so
فلنقل أن لدينا نقطة البيانات هذه التي لديها اثنان awesomes وواحدة awful،
let's call that input x1.
دعونا نطلق على هذا الإدخال x1.
And we're going to try to output y1 which is this is a positive sentiment.
وسنقوم بمحاولة إخراج y1 وهو شعور إيجابي.
This is a review of positive sentiment.
فهذا هو استعراض للشعور الإيجابي.
If our classifier were really good, if ws were good, what would happen?
إذا كان لدينا تصنيف جيد حقًا، إذا كانت ws جيدة، ما الذي سيحدث؟
Well for this particular input you would output y hat for 1 is also equal to +1.
حسنًا لهذا الإدخال الخاصة سوف تقوم بإخراج y hat لـ 1 أيضًا يساوي +1.
In other words, y hat agrees with the true label y.
وبعبارة أخرى، تتوافق y hat مع تسمية y الحقيقية.
So what should we do for y hat to agree with the true label y,
إذًا ماذا نفعل حتى تتفق y hat مع تسمية y الحقيقية،
we're using logistic regression.
سنستخدم الانحدار اللوجستي.
Well we're going to try to find w that
حسنًا سنحاول إيجاد w التي
makes the probability that y = +1,
تجعل الاحتمالية أن y = +1،
when the input is x1.
عندما يكون الإدخال هو x1.
And the parameter's w, we're going to make that as big as possible.
وبالنسبة للمتغير w، فسنجعله كبيرًا قدر الإمكان.
In other words, we want to make the probability that y = +1,
وبعبارة أخرى، نحن نريد أن نجري الاحتمالية أن y = +1،
when x1, number of awesomes is 2, and x2,
عندما x1، وعدد مرات awesome هو 2 وx2،
number of awfuls is 1 for the parameter w.
عدد مرات awful هو 1 للمتغير w.
We're going to make that probability as big as possible.
وسنقوم بجعل هذه الاحتمالية كبيرة قدر الإمكان.
But that was for a positive example.
ولكن كان ذلك لمثال إيجابي.
We're going to make the probability of y = +1 as big as possible.
وسنقوم بجعل احتمالية y = +1 كبيرة قدر الإمكان.
Now let's take another example.
والآن لنأخذ مثالًا آخر.
Let's call this example x2, where had 0 awesomes and 2 awfuls,
دعونا نطلق على هذا المثال x2، حيث لدينا 0 مرة awesome و2 مرة awful،
must be an awful review, awful restaurant.
يجب أن يكون تقييم سيء، مطعم سيء.
And so the sentiment for y2 is -1.
وبذلك يكون الشعور لـ y2 هو -1.
So if our classify is good, if w is good,
حتى إذا كان تصنيفنا جيد، إذا كان w جيدًا،
in this case when it should predict that y hat 2 = -1.
في هذه الحالة عندما ينبغي توقع أن y hat 2 = -1.
So, agree with the true label.
لذا، تتفق مع التسمية الحقيقية.
So in this case, we're not maximizing the probability of y = 1.
إذًا في هذه الحالة، نحن لا نقوم بتكبير احتمالية y = 1.
But, we're maximizing the probability that y
ولكن، نحن تقوم بتكبير احتمالية أن y
= -1 when the input is x2 for the parameters w.
=-1 عندما يكون الإدخال هو x2 للمتغير w.
In other words, when the input is x1,
وبعبارة أخرى، عندما يكون الإدخال x1،
we'll maximize the probability that y = +1.
فسوف نقوم بتكبير احتمالية أن y = +1.
And when we put this x2, we want to maximize the probability that y = -1.
وعندما نضع x2 1 تصبح الاحتمالية y =-1.
That's what the data likelihood tries to do, but let's dig in and
وهذا هو ما يحاول احتمال البيانات القيام به، ولكن دعونا نبحث في الأمر
understand that a little bit better.
ونحاول أن نفهم بشكل أفضل قليلًا.
Now we just don't have two training examples, we have a ton of examples.
والآن ليس لدينا مجرد مثالين على التدريب، بل لدينا طن من الأمثلة.
We have a big dataset.
لدينا مجموعة بيانات كبيرة.
So what are we trying to do?
إذًا ما الذي نحاول القيام به؟
So let's look at the first example.
حسنًا دعونا ننظر إلى المثال الأول.
In the first example, we want to maximize,
في المثال الأول، نحن نريد أن نزيد الاحتمالية،
since this is a positive example, we're going to maximize
نظرًا لأن هذا مثال إيجابي، فنحن نريد زيادة الاحتمالية
the probability that y is equal to +1 when the input is x1.
بأن y يساوي +1 عندما يكون لإدخال هو x1.
And the parameters are w, so
والمتغيرات هي w، لذا ففي
in this case is the probability that y =
هذه الحالة تكون احتمالية أن y =
+1 when the number of awesomes is 2 and
+1 عندما يكون عدد مرات awesome هو 2
the number of awfuls is 1, and the parameter is w.
وعدد مرات awful هو 1، والمتغير هو w.
So we try to make the probability y = +1 given x1 to be as big as possible.
ولذلك نحن نحاول أن نجعل احتمالية أن y = +1 مع معرفة x1 تكون كبيرة قدر الإمكان.
For the next example, we're trying to make the probability that y = -1
بالنسبة للمثال التالي، سنحاول جعل احتمالية أن y =-1
given x2, w to be to be as big as possible as a negative example.
مع إعطاء x2، وتكون w كبيرة قدر الإمكان كمثال سلبي.
For the third one is also a negative example, so
وبالنسبة للمثال الثالثـ وهو أيضًا مثال سلبي، لذا
we're trying to make the probability that y = -1 given x to be nw.
فنحن نسعى لجعل احتمالية أن y = -1 مع إعطاء x لتكون nw.
For the fourth one, we're trying to make the probability that y,
وبالنسبة للمثال الرابع، نحن نسعى لإجراء احتمالية أن y،
it's a positive example, so y = +1 given x4 and w as large as possible.
وهو مثال إيجابي، حيث y = +1 مع إعطاء x4 وw كبيرة بقدر الإمكان.
So in other words, for the possible example of trying to make the probability
لذلك وبعبارة أخرى، بالنسبة للمثال الممكن لمحاولة إجراء الاحتمالية
y = +1 as big as possible for negative examples, we're trying
y = +1 كبيرة مثل قدر الإمكان للأمثلة السلبية، نحن نحاول
to make the probability y = -1 as big as possible, which is pretty natural.
إجراء احتمالية y =-1 كبيرة قدر الإمكان، وهو أمر طبيعي جدًا.
And we want to do that for each example, for every single one of those.
ونحن نريد أن تفعل ذلك لكل مثال، لكل واحد منها.
Now the question is how do we combine,
والآن السؤال هو كيف نجمع،
like for a single quality metric, how do we combine these?
مثل لمقياس جودة واحد، كيف نجمع بين هذه؟
And you can imagine multiple ways of combining this averages,
ويمكنك أن تتخيل طرق متعددة للجمع بين هذه المتوسطات،
I don't know, all sorts of ideas out there.
أنا لا أعرف، كل أنواع الأفكار هنا.
The way that you typically combine when you're doing what's called maximizing
الطريقة التي تقوم بها بالجمع عادة عندما تقوم بما يسمى بتكبير
likelihood estimation or
تقدير الاحتمال أو
maximizing likelihood is by multiplying these things together.
تعظيم الاحتمالات هي بضرب هذه الأشياء معًا.
So you multiply.
لذا فستقوم بالضرب.
So, in other words, you say that it's the product of y = +1 given,
وبعبارة أخرى، يمكنك أن تقول إنه ناتج y = +1،
that's from the first line.
معطى، وهذا من السطر الأول.
Given x1 and w times the probability that y = -1 from
مع إعطاء x1 وw ضرب احتمالية أن y =-1 من
the second line here given x2 and w, and the third line is also negative.
السطر الثاني هنا مع إعطاء x2 وw، والسطر الثالث أيضًا سلبي.
So, times the probability that y = -1 given x3, w and so on.
لذا فبالضرب في احتمالية أن y =-1 مع إعطاء x3، w وهكذا.
So you just multiply them all together.
إذًا أنت تقوم بضرب كل شيء معًا.
Here's a side little note who those who know about probabilities.
إليكم ملاحظة جانبية صغيرة لأولئك الذين لديهم معرفة بالاحتمالات.
The reason you multiply is that you assume that every row is independent
السبب وراء قيامك بالضرب هو أنك تفترض أن كل صف من الصفوف يكون مستقلًا
of each other.
عن بعضها البعض.
So, there's an independence that comes into play, but
لذا، فهناك عامل الاستقلال الذي يلعب دورًا، ولكن
don't worry too much about this.
لا تقلق كثيرًا بشأن ذلك.
Just think about as a multiplication.
فقط فكر في الأمر كعملية ضرب.
Okay, so let's do that a little bit more explicitly.
حسنًا، دعونا نفعل ذلك بشكل أوضح قليلًا.
Now we have these data points 1 through 4, and for
الآن لدينا نقاط البيانات هذه من 1 إلى 4، وبالنسبة لكل
each one of them we're trying to maximize the specific probability.
واحدة منها نحن نحاول زيادة الاحتمالية المحددة لها إلى أقصى حد.
So for the positive examples, we're trying to maximize probability of y = +1, for
لذا بالنسبة للأمثلة الإيجابية، نحن نحاول زيادة احتمالية أن y = +1، وبالنسبة إلى
the negative examples of probability y = -1.
للأمثلة السلبية نحاول زيادة احتمالية y =-1.
Given the parameter w, we're going to find w that makes those as big as possible.
مع إعطاء المتغير w، سنقوم بإيجاد w الذي يجعل تلك الاحتماليات كبيرة قدر الإمكان.
So the likelihood function, the thing in which we want to optimize
لذا فإن دالة الاحتمال تعمل، وهي الشيء الذي يكون فيه
is the product of each one of these probabilities.
[غير مسموع] هو ناتج كل واحدة من هذه الاحتماليات.
I like that animation.
أنا أحب هذه الحركة.
It's pretty cool?
إنها رائعة أليس كذلك؟.
So, we're going to use a shorthand notation here.
لذا، سنقوم باستخدام ترميز مختصر هنا.
So for the first example, we have that y1 up here, was +1.
لذا بالنسبة للمثال الأول، لدينا أن y1 هنا، كانت +1.
So we're going to denote that by probability of y1, given x1 and w.
وبالتالي سنقوم بترميز ذلك باحتمالية y1 مع إعطاء x1 وw.
So, the y1's going to get from this +1, and
لذا فإن y1 سيتم الحصول عليها من +1 هذا،
x1 is going to come from this representation of x.
وسوف تأتي x1 من هذا التمثيل لـ x.
And similarly for the other one, so the notation's going to get long and heavy.
وبالمثل للآخر، لذا فسيصبح الترميز طويلًا وثقيلًا.
We just say probability of y1 given x1 and
ونحن نقول فقط احتمالية y1 بإعطاء x1
that would be the probability of y2 given x2 and w.
وستكون هذه هي احتمالية y2 بإعطاء x2 وw.
Probability of y3 given x3 and w, and we're just multiplying them together.
واحتمالية y3 بإعطاء x3 وw، وسنقوم فقط بضربها معًا.
And finally so that that line doesn't get really long, because if we have
وأخيرًا، وحتى لا يصبح هذا السطر طويلًا جدًا، لأنه إذا كان لدينا
a million or two examples, we would have a million of these entries.
1 أو 2 مليون مثال، فسيكون لدينا 1 مليون من هذه الإدخالات.
We use the product notation.
ونحن نستخدم ترميز الناتج.
So this is the little notation over here.
لذا فهذا هو الترميز هنا.
And it just says, I'm just going to write same function here.
وهو يقول، سأقوم فقط بكتابة بعض الدوال هنا.
l(w) is going to be equal to the product
(l(w سوف تكون مساوية للناتج
that ranges from the first data point to n,
الذي يتراوح بين نقطة البيانات الأولى وn،
which is number of data points of the probability
وهو عدد نقاط البيانات لاحتمالية
of whatever label yi has, +1, -1.
أن أيًا كانت تسمية y، ستساوي +1، -1.
Given the input xi, which is the sentence of that review, and the parameter w.
مع إعطاء للإدخال xi، الذي هو حالة هذا التقييم، والمتغير w.
This is the likelihood function that we're trying to optimize.
وهذه هي دالة الاحتمال التي نحاول تحسينها.
So, our goal here is to pick
لذا فإن هدفنا هنا هو اختيار
w to make this crazy thing,
w لجعل هذا الشيء المجنون،
I mean, this function as
أعني، هذه الدالة
large as possible.
كبيرة بقدر الإمكان.
That's our goal.
وهذا هو هدفنا.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]